

# Stephen Mogavero

in Stephen-Mogavero 📋 https://smogavero4.github.io/Resume 🦲 GitHub/Smogavero4





Smogavero4@gmail.com



(845) 264-1443

## **IT Analyst**

# **Education:**

**State University of New York College at Buffalo** 

Bachelor of Science **Computer Information Systems** 2019 - **GPA 3.94** 

**Monroe Community College** 

Associate of Science **Computer Information Systems** 2016

# **Certification:**

**Google IT Support Specialization** Coursera - Nov 2019



**Data Center University Associate Development Path** 

(DCCA) - Mar 2019 Schneider Electric

**A+ Computer Repair** Certification

**Dutchess BOCES - 2013** 

# **Awards:**

**Excellence in Computer Information Systems** 

SUNY Buffalo State - 2019 This award is given to a few graduating CIS majors who have demonstrated outstanding academic achievement

## **Exemplary Character and** Citizenship

Dwight Bonk (Principal JJHS) 2013

The award recognizes outstanding high school students who do the right thing, are responsible and go out of their way to be kind to others.

# **Summary:**

Self-motivated with excellent organization and communication skills, along with a strong IT background in infrastructure management and programming. Exceptional attention to detail and the ability to make data-driven decisions with business intelligence software. Seven years of experience in PC and server hardware and software troubleshooting.

## **Experience:**

## **BlackRock - Data Center Engineer**

- Communicate with global teams to obtain IT project requirements.
- Evaluate and analyze project requirements and determine the best course of action.
- Analyze facility data and create utilization forecasts to optimize space and power usage.

Jan. 2019 to Current

Feb. 2017 to Jan.2019

- Coordinate with on-site team members to fulfill project requirements.
- Discuss and resolve project issues that arise and offer solutions.
- · Rack, cable, and install servers and data center hardware. Diagnose and troubleshoot hardware and software issues.

## **Deluxe - Data Center Operations Coordinator**

- Reports to the Director of Information Technology. Directs operations staff throughout the shift.
- Oversee project completion using Agile methodologies.
- · Document data center processes and procedures.
- Hold meetings with clients and gather project requirements.
- Hold team meetings to plan and set goals for projects.
- Review project results and determine where process improvements can be made.

## Outback Steakhouse – Key Manager

- Responsible for bar inventory and dining room operations.
- · Ensure great guest experiences and resolve any issues that arise.
- Jan. 2016 to Feb. 2017 Analyze customer reviews and determine
- where improvements can be made.
- · Monitor team performance and strategically place serving staff.

## **USS Starcross LLC – IT Manager**

- Build relationships with residential and commercial clients.
- Troubleshoot Windows and Linux based systems.

Jul. 2012 to Aug. 2016

- Oversee a team of 10 technicians.
- · Installed residential and commercial network wiring and wireless systems.

# **Projects:**

**Skills:** 

#### **BlackRock** Oct. 2019 **Data Center Training Program**

# • Developed a global training program for

- BlackRock's data center engineers • Included an interactive PowerPoint with questions on best practices.
- Created a 50-question multiple-choice exam and tracked training online.

### BlackRock

Apr. 2019

# **Utilization Forecasts (VBA)**

- Automated a monthly report that shows global data center utilization.
- Created using Microsoft Excel and PowerPoint utilizing VBA to web scrape data from monitoring devices.

#### **Management:**

- Agile Project Management
- Teamwork Leadership
- Training & Development
- Problem Solving
- Analytics

#### Technical:

- Microsoft Office
- Windows OS
- SQL Python
- Troubleshooting
- Linux OS
- Data Modeling
- Documentation